A Guide to Northumberland County (Va.) Organization Records, circa 1765-1935
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Northumberland County (Va.) Organization Records, circa 1765-1935
The Library of Virginia
1133933, 1180694, 1180696, 1180700, 1180745, 1180748, 1180756-1180759, 1180761-1180763, 1180766-1180768, 1180770, 1180771, 1180791-1180793, 1180801, and 1182759.
23 boxes
Northumberland County (Va.) Circuit Court.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These items came to the Library of Virginia in records transfers from Northumberland County under accession numbers 43283, 43487, and unknown.
Historical Information
Northumberland County was named probably for the English county. It was formed about 1645 from the district of Chickacoan, the early-seventeenth-century name for the region between the Potomac and the Rappahannock Rivers. The date of the county's formation is conjectural because the act of assembly creating it is no longer extant, but internal evidence shows that the county was functioning in 1645.
The county suffered some losses in a fire in the clerk’s office on October 25, 1710. Volumes beginning in 1650 that record deeds, court orders, and wills exist.
Scope and Content
Northumberland County (Va.) Organization Records, circa 1765-1935, typically consist of appointments of trustees, minutes, and miscellaneous records of religious organizations, fraternal organizations, independent associations, and cooperatives.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Additional Northumberland County records can be found on microfilm at the Library of Virginia. Consult "A Guide to Virginia County and City Records on Microfilm" found on the Library of Virginia's web site.
Additional Northumberland County Records may be found in the Virginia Lost Records Localities Collection at the Library of Virginia. Search the Lost Records Localities Digital Collection.
For more information and a listing of lost records localities see Lost Records research note.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Northumberland (Va.) Circuit Court.
Subjects:
Public records--Virginia--Northumberland County.; Organization records--Virginia--Northumberland County.
Geographical Names:
Northumberland County (Va.)--History.
Genre and Form Terms:
Local government records--Virginia--Northumberland County.
Contents List
- Northumberland County, Various Series, 1765-1868 (includes Organization Records, 1849).
- Northumberland County, Judgments, circa 1850-1862 (includes Organization Records, unprocessed).
- Northumberland County, Judgments, circa 1870-1889 (includes Organization Records, unprocessed).
- Northumberland County, Judgments, 1881-1899 (includes Organization Records, unprocessed).
- Northumberland County, Court Papers, 1882-1883 (includes Organization Records, unprocessed).
- Northumberland County, Court Papers, 1887 (includes Organization Records, unprocessed).
- Northumberland County, Court Papers, 1895-1897 (includes Organization Records, unprocessed).
- Northumberland County, Court Papers, 1895-1898 (includes Organization Records, unprocessed).
- Northumberland County, Court Papers, 1897-1899 (includes Organization Records, unprocessed).
- Northumberland County, Court Papers, 1900-1902 (includes Organization Records, unprocessed).
- Northumberland County, Court Papers, 1903-1904 (includes Organization Records, unprocessed).
- Northumberland County, Court Papers, 1905-1906 (includes Organization Records, unprocessed).
- Northumberland County, Court Papers, circa 1902-1908 (includes Organization Records, unprocessed).
- Northumberland County, Court Papers, 1911-1916 (includes Organization Records, unprocessed).
- Northumberland County, Court Papers, 1917-1919 (includes Organization Records, unprocessed).
- Northumberland County, Misc. Old Papers, 1795-1802 (includes Organization Records, unprocessed).
- Northumberland County, Misc. Old Papers, circa 1821-1935 (includes Organization Records, unprocessed).
- Northumberland County, Misc. Old Papers, circa 1830-1935 (includes Organization Records, unprocessed).
- Northumberland County, Court Papers, 1848-1850 (includes Organization Records, unprocessed).
- Northumberland County, Court Papers, 1850-1865, 1884-1885 (includes Organization Records, unprocessed).
- Northumberland County, Court Papers, 1851-1853 (includes Organization Records, unprocessed).
- Northumberland County, Court Papers, 1872-1875 (includes Organization Records, unprocessed).
- Northumberland County, Various Series, circa 1785-1921 (includes Organization Records, 1912).